a man be found faithful.
And it ought to be the desire of every one of us
to live lives that are faithful
so that those that come behind us
would have an example to follow.
And what a blessing, thank the Lord for that song.
Luke chapter number one,
if you have your Bible with you this morning,
and Luke chapter number one,
and let me just share a couple of things
by way of introduction
as we get into the message this morning.
And of course we have mentioned,
and we're gonna have some things
after the service this morning
with regard to Anniversary Sunday.
And it's not the anniversary of the church,
that's in October,
but it's the anniversary of us being here as the pastor.
And the month of August
actually is a very important special month to me personally.
And on August 31st of this year,
it'll be 29 years since I trusted Christ
as my personal savior.
And I'm so thankful for that day
that Christ changed my life, amen.
If any man be in Christ, he is a new creature.
Old things are passed away,
behold, all things are become new.
And I thank the Lord for his grace
and for his mercy saving my soul.
And that's 29 years ago on August 31st.
And then of course our wedding anniversary,
a milestone this month on the 20th.
So just in about 10 days or so,
Holly and I will celebrate 25 years of marriage.
And I'm reminded, the Bible says,
"'Whoso findeth a wife, findeth a good thing
"'and obtaineth favor of the Lord.'"
Amen.
And I am so thankful for Holly,
thankful for the opportunity that God has given us
to serve the Lord together.
And it's been a great, just a,
she's a great wife, a mother to our children.
I thank God for her every day
and praise the Lord for the opportunity
to meet that milestone.
I know some of you recently hit 55 years
and by God's grace, we'll get there.
But I am looking for the return of the Lord, amen.
And listen for the trumpet, Jesus is coming, amen.
And that'd be okay.
But then of course, this past Friday
was 15 years that I've been able to serve
as the pastor here at Fellowship Baptist Church.
And very thankful for that opportunity and that privilege.
I remember going to Bible college
and knowing that the Lord called me to pastor
as I changed majors and studied pastoral theology.
And then it's like, where are you gonna end up?
Where are you gonna go and serve the Lord
in a number of ministries
and had the opportunity to be able to work
in the corporate world as we were learning more
about ministry and serving.
And just thank the Lord for each stage.
And then we knew it was time to go pastor a church.
And then how do you figure that out?
And we were talking on Sunday night,
Brother Kevin was asking questions
about how do you find those things out?
And I had some mentors that I thank God for.
And Sallie Nizzie was my pastor
and Palmer Sean was my mentor.
And I'd been in the corporate world
for a long time at that point.
And networking and all of that
was something that was very custom
and who you knew was very important.
And they said, God knows where you are.
He knows where you need to be.
Just keep serving God and let him open a door.
And I said, well, God is God and he is able.
And so we'll just continue to serve the Lord
and then God opened the door here
and very thankful for the opportunity of ministry.
It's been a blessing to serve the Lord together
and to see all that God has done.
I have you here in Luke chapter number one
but I wanna share a few verses of scriptures.
I think about these wonderful things
that I've just been able to rehearse for you.
I'm reminded a verse that I claimed
as a life verse going to Bible college.
First Thessalonians five and verse 24,
faithful is he who calleth you who also will do it.
And I'm thankful that they were able to sing
about faithful men and those that have gone before us.
But I want to remind you this morning
that our God is faithful.
Great is thy faithfulness, amen.
And we're gonna rejoice in knowing
that we serve a faithful God.
David said this in Psalm 34 and verse number 80,
taste and see that the Lord is good.
Blessed is the man that trusteth in him
and God is good all of the time.
I have a little note card on my desk
and it says this, we praise God
not because things are always good
but because he is always good.
And God is good all of the time
and we're thankful for that.
Peter would say this in first Peter two,
the beginning part of verse number seven,
he would say unto you therefore which believe,
he is precious.
And I hope this morning that you have trusted Jesus Christ
as your personal savior
and that you too would agree with Peter
in saying that the Lord is precious, amen.
And I'm so thankful.
And then I think of this verse,
it's a life verse that Holly uses as her life verse
but so thankful for the Bible
in first Timothy chapter one and verse number 12,
the Bible says this, Paul is rehearsing
and he says I thank Christ Jesus our Lord
who hath enabled me for that he counted me faithful
putting me into the ministry.
And I'm thankful that I have the opportunity
to serve alongside Holly and the pastorate
and being in the ministry in this capacity
but the reality is that every single one of us
have a ministry and we understand
the Ephesians teaches about the fact
that God has given to the church as a gift,
pastors and teachers
and it says for the edifying of the believers
for the work of the ministry
and we all have a ministry
and we're thankful that we can serve the Lord together.
In Luke chapter number one,
I have you there in that passage of scripture
and here in Luke chapter number one,
Mary receives word with regard to her place in God's plan
with regard to the birth of the Lord Jesus Christ,
our wonderful savior.
And you imagine the encounter
and we won't look at all of that this morning,
many of us are familiar with Luke chapter number one
but we find that she receives that wonderful word
and of course we understand as Galatians would say it
that at the right time, right?
We find that God sent forth his son
when the fullness of time was come,
God sent forth his son
and I'm thankful that Mary received this information
and after receiving this vision
and understanding the plan of God
and her part in God's plan,
the Bible tells us that she went into the hill country
and she had some interaction with her cousin Elizabeth.
Now Elizabeth had received some interesting information
earlier in the chapter,
Zacharias was serving in his role
and had received a vision as well
with regard to the birth of John the Baptist
and we find that there's interaction there
and I want you to notice
that as they have this interaction
and we find that Elizabeth is speaking to Mary
and all these things take place
but then we find that Mary begins to speak
and we're gonna look at verse 46
and we're gonna go down through verse number 55
and notice what the Bible says in verse 46
and Mary said, notice this,
"'My soul doth magnify the Lord
"'and my spirit hath rejoiced in God my Savior,
"'for he hath regarded the lowest state of his handmaiden
"'for behold from henceforth
"'all generations shall call me blessed,
"'for he that is mighty hath done to me great things
"'and holy is his name
"'and his mercy is on them that fear him
"'from generation to generation.
"'He hath showed strength with his arm.
"'He hath scattered the proud
"'in the imagination of their hearts.
"'He hath put down the mighty from their seats
"'and exalted them of low degree.
"'He hath filled the hungry with good things
"'and the rich he hath sent away empty.
"'He hath hope and has served in Israel
"'in remembrance of his mercy
"'as he spake to our fathers,
"'to Abraham and to his seed forever.'"
I've simply titled the message this morning
from verse number 46,
my soul doth magnify the Lord.
We find here as we look in the text of scripture
that God gives us the reasons
by which Mary is magnifying the Lord.
But I would say for us this morning
as we look at this text of scripture
that each one of us in our lives
should be magnifying the Lord.
The Psalmist said this in Psalm 70 in verse number four,
let God be magnified.
And we think about the importance of this idea
of magnifying the Lord
and understanding in the life of Mary
contextually as we look here.
But then in your life and in my life,
see we deal with all sorts of things
as we go through life
and you deal with trials and troubles and circumstances.
And there are times in which those outside influences
can affect us and impact us.
And maybe we go through life
focusing more upon our problems and the circumstances
than we do on our God.
And maybe in those moments of difficulty and hardship
and all that's taking place,
we stop magnifying the Lord
because really what we're doing is magnifying our problems.
And it's a real danger for all of us
as we live in this world.
And we understand that Jesus said that we're in the world,
but we're not of the world.
And we understand that he's given us all things
that pertain unto life and godliness.
We've been teaching on Wednesdays
through the book of 2 John
and there's only 13 verses.
Surely we could have gone through it in one week,
but we're going into week number five here on Wednesday.
And we're only a few verses into the book
because it's so rich and there's so much for us.
And last week we looked at that truth where he said,
grace, peace, or sorry, grace, mercy, and peace.
And you think about the grace of God
and the mercy of God in your life
and how it brings peace.
The result of God's grace and God's mercy, it brings peace.
And the reality this morning is that we as the people
the people of God, we must magnify the Lord.
It is absolutely imperative that the world in which we live
understands that we have a great God, amen?
Great is the Lord and greatly to be praised.
The Psalmist begins that way in Psalm 48
and then he ends that particular Psalm
by speaking about this God is our God forever.
Now think about that this morning.
He is worthy of our praise and it is absolutely essential
that we would magnify the Lord in our lives.
So what is it that caused Mary to magnify the Lord?
What is it that will cause you and me to magnify the Lord,
to lift him up, to exalt him?
And we think about the importance.
Remember John said this, John the Baptist said this,
he must increase, I must decrease.
It's all about Jesus.
It's all about God being magnified.
Sometimes we live in a world and we see it happen
where people are concerned and consumed
with making a name for themselves.
You know what I'm thankful for?
We don't have to make a name for ourselves.
We magnify the Lord.
It's all about Jesus.
Listen, I know that in me there is no good, right?
We understand that without him, we can do nothing.
We understand that we are what we are by the grace of God.
And so as you live your life and as I live my life,
we ought to desire to magnify the Lord.
And so let's look through the passage,
a couple of thoughts for you this morning.
Number one, I will magnify the Lord
when I focus on his person, who he is.
Think about how great our God is.
You know, everything that you know about God,
you know because he's given us a Bible.
The truth that we have, that we rejoice in,
the attributes of God that we share with others,
we know those because God has given to us a Bible.
And I'm so thankful this morning
that as we look here at this text of scripture,
we're reminded by the life of Mary
and even the things that she says
that she's magnifying the Lord
because she's focused on the person, who God is.
And for us this morning, we must focus on who God is.
Looking unto Jesus, the author and finisher of our faith,
we understand that the psalmist said,
I will lift up mine eyes into the hills
from whence cometh my help.
My help cometh from the Lord, which made heaven and earth.
The reality this morning is that
where you focus is important.
Who you focus upon is important.
We find that as we look here at the text of scripture,
there's really six thoughts that we find here
that Mary would reveal here through this interaction
with Elizabeth with regard to what she's recognizing
to be true and how it is resulting in her life
of magnifying the Lord.
She said, my soul doth magnify the Lord
and my spirit hath rejoiced in God my savior.
Under this thought of I will magnify the Lord
when I focus on his person,
recognize with me this morning, number one, he is mighty.
He is mighty.
Aren't you thankful that our God is omnipotent?
He has all power.
There's nothing that's too hard for him.
We find that first asked of Abraham
and God had appeared to Abraham
several times and had given various names to Abraham
with regard to who he was,
revealing different aspects of his character and nature.
But we find that in Genesis, he comes to Abraham
and he says to him, I'm the Lord God Almighty.
That Hebrew word is El Shaddai.
And we find that he reveals this truth to Abraham.
Now he had given a promise to Abraham and Sarah
with regard to having a child, a son.
We find that he would be the heir and it would be Isaac.
And you read through the passage and you see that later on
in the chapters of the book of Genesis.
But we find that after God revealed himself to Abraham
as being the Lord God Almighty,
he then asks Abraham this question,
is anything too hard for the Lord?
Now, I think that's kind of like a setup.
Amen?
He tells him, I'm the Lord God Almighty.
He tells him how powerful he is
and then says, is anything too hard for me?
Well, no, of course not.
You just told me that you're the Lord God Almighty.
And see, this morning as we think about
the passage of scripture in verse number 49,
it says, for he that is mighty.
Our God is mighty.
He'll say here in Luke chapter number one,
in verse number 37, for with God,
nothing shall be impossible.
We're reminded of the wonderful prayer promise
in Ephesians three and verse number 20.
Now unto him which is able to do exceeding,
abundantly above all that we ask or think.
We begin to rejoice this morning and magnify the Lord.
Why?
Because of his power, because he is mighty,
because he is omnipotent.
And I understand this morning that we have issues in life.
We have problems, we have various circumstances,
but I want you to remember that my help cometh
from the Lord which made heaven and earth.
For a couple of days this past week,
we had the opportunity to go over to West Virginia.
And they have some ideas over there in West Virginia
that I don't think are really biblical.
They call it almost heaven.
Now it's nice over there, but I'm telling you what,
it's gonna be a lot better in heaven
because Jesus is gonna be there, amen?
And, but it's a beautiful place, wild and beautiful,
and we got to see a number of things.
But on Friday evening, we're over by a lake
and we looked up at the stars.
And I'm gonna tell you what, Holly and I,
on our 10-year wedding anniversary,
we went over to Sedona, Arizona, up into the Grand Canyon,
and we're out there at night and seeing the stars.
And at that point I thought,
man, I've never seen stars like this.
Just absolutely amazing.
Until last Friday night,
because it was even more magnificent.
I mean, it was amazing.
There's no light pollution and you can just see,
I saw more stars on Friday night
than I've ever seen in my life.
It was amazing.
As we stood there, we're looking up into the stars
and looking up in the sky and trying to stay out of the lake
because it was dark and you couldn't see real good.
But we're looking up and I said this to the family.
I said, you know, it's amazing to me.
I said, when you think about the record of Genesis,
that it's just five words, he made the stars also.
And I think it was Joseph that said,
and he says, he calls them all by name.
Yeah, that's in the book of Psalms.
And Brianna said,
I don't think I could even think of that many names.
Amen.
Listen, our God is almighty.
He is powerful.
He made the stars also.
I mean, it's just almost just a passing statement
in the Genesis record of creation.
And he is our divine helper.
And Mary says, he that is mighty.
And I want you to think about,
hey, we need to magnify the Lord.
We live in a world, sometimes we can get sideways
and we say, how are all these crazy things going on?
I mean, what is going on?
Things are falling apart.
Listen, our world needs to know that we serve a great God
and we need to magnify the Lord.
And when we focus on his person, that he is mighty,
not only is he mighty, but we see number two,
look there in verse number 49,
he that is mighty hath done to me great things
and holy is his name.
Our God is mighty, but our God is holy.
We find that throughout the scriptures,
you find the truth of the holiness of God.
And I'm thankful the psalmist tells us
that we're to give thanks
at the remembrance of his holiness.
We find that as you look in the book of Leviticus,
that God is teaching his people that they are to be holy.
Why? Because he is holy.
Peter would then state that again in his epistle
in first Peter, that we as the people of God
are to be holy because our God is holy.
I'm of course reminded,
and maybe your mind would immediately go there as well.
When you think about the account in Isaiah chapter number six
when Isaiah sees God and all of his holiness,
and he sees God high, holy and lifted up
and the train did fill the temple.
And the Bible says that he hears those angels saying,
holy, holy, holy.
Listen, this morning we need to rejoice
and we need to magnify the Lord because he's mighty,
but also because he's holy.
God's not becoming holy, he is holy.
We find that not only does Mary reference in verse 49,
that God is mighty and that God is holy,
but we find number three in verse number 50,
notice it says, and his mercy is on them
that fear him from generation to generation.
Aren't you thankful for God's mercy?
In Ephesians chapter two in verse number four,
the Bible says, but God who is rich in mercy
for his great love wherewith he has loved us.
And we think about the mercy of God,
his mercies are new every morning,
Jeremiah tells us in the book of Lamentations.
And we begin to think about the mercy of God
and that he's merciful.
In the Psalms, the Bible tells us
that his mercy endureth forever.
That's for us as the people of God.
And I'm so thankful that our God is merciful.
We dealt with that a little bit on Wednesday evening,
grace, mercy and peace.
And we said that grace is God giving us
what we do not deserve,
but mercy is God not giving us what we do deserve.
And truly as sinners, we deserve the lake of fire,
but God is merciful.
And I'm so thankful for his mercy.
Remember, we looked there at the passage
in Hebrews four in verse number 16,
and that were to come boldly into the throne of grace,
that we may obtain mercy and find grace
to help in time of need.
And I'm thankful for the mercy of God.
And here, Mary is.
magnifying the Lord. She said, My soul doth magnify the Lord.
My spirit hath rejoiced in God my Savior. Why? Because he's
mighty. Why? Because he's holy. Why? Because he's merciful. We
find number four there in verse 50. It's also repeated in verse
number 55. I want you to think about this when you focus on who
God is, when you focus on his person, that he is eternal. He's
eternal. Notice in verse 50, and his mercy is on them that fear
him. Notice what it says from generation to generation. In
verse number 55, as he spake to our fathers, to Abraham and to
his seed forever. I'm thankful this morning that our God is
Alpha and Omega. I'm thankful this morning that he's eternal.
He has no beginning and no ending. He is outside of time.
And some of you wish you were outside of time because of all
the constraints that time would put upon us and you wouldn't be
told you're late anymore and all of that sort of thing. But
listen, our God is always in the present because he's eternal.
What a blessing to think about that. We begin to consider the
things that we face in our lives and we understand that there's
some people that would have that perspective of life that it's
just never been this way and no one understands. But God is
eternal so he understands perfectly. We find that he is
Alpha and Omega. We find that John would say it this way, we
won't turn there. But in John chapter number 1, as he's going
through and he's talking about the deity of Christ, the person
of Christ, and he's making some comments there with regard to
John the Baptist. And he talks about the fact that John the
Baptist is going to say this, that he is preferred above me
because he was before me. Now we understand if you were to look
at it from a strictly human perspective, chronologically,
John the Baptist is born first and then Jesus Christ. But John
the Baptist could accurately say that Jesus was before him because
he is eternal. What a blessing to understand this morning that
our God is eternal. The songwriter said this, I don't
know what's on the morrow, but I know who holds tomorrow in his
hand. Amen? Because he lives, I can face tomorrow. Right? You
don't know. Some of us worry about tomorrow. And by the way,
the Bible says be careful for nothing. And we're not to worry.
We're to trust, to have faith and understand that God knows
and God cares and God is there. And we find that he is eternal.
He is, if you're taking notes, when I focus on his person I'm
going to magnify him. Why? Number 5, because he is the
strong one. And we understand as we talked already about the
fact that he is mighty. But notice in verse 51, he hath
showed strength with his arm. See, I love the truth of God's
word that when he speaks to us about his attributes, that he
not only declares them, but he also demonstrates them. It's one
thing for God to tell us that he has all power. And it's quite
another thing for us to see where God demonstrates that he
has all power. It's one thing for God to tell Abraham, is
anything too hard for me? And it's another thing for God to
give Abraham and Sarah a son when he's 100 and she's 90. You
begin to think about the blessing of the Lord and the
demonstration of his power. And you find that as you go through
the scriptures and you see the power of God, he is the strong
one and he is my strength. Remember what Paul said when he
spoke there in 2 Corinthians chapter number 12 with regard to
the thorn in his flesh? He prayed. And I believe that God
could have removed that thorn in his side, in his flesh. He could
have removed that. We find that God said, my grace is
sufficient for thee. And then he tells them that my strength is
made perfect in weakness. And Paul says something at the end
of that chapter that is absolutely convicting when you
begin to think about our lives and the reality of what God has
told Paul. Because then Paul says this, most gladly therefore
will I rather glory in my infirmities that the power of
Christ may rest upon me. Therefore, I take pleasure in
infirmities, in reproaches, in necessities, in persecutions, in
distresses for Christ's sake. For when I am weak, then am I
strong. Amen. What a blessing to think about the fact that the
one who is the strong one, the one who hath showed strength,
that he is my strength. I am so thankful this morning. Listen,
the songwriter said the arm of flesh will fail you. And it
will. It absolutely will. But they that wait upon the Lord
shall renew their strength. Amen. Isaiah 40 and verse
number 31. And you begin to think about the reason as Mary
here is saying, my soul doth magnify the Lord. And I say to
each of us this morning, we ought to also be in that
position where we are magnifying the Lord. And if we were to
focus upon his person, I believe it will result in us
magnifying the Lord. Number six, in verse number 52, we find
that Mary reveals to us here in this speech that he, our God,
is just. Notice it says in verse 52, he hath put down the
mighty from their seats and exalteth them of low degree.
The Bible tells it this way to us, that God resisteth the
proud, but giveth grace unto the humble. And we find that our
God is just. And I'm thankful this morning that he is a just
God. And we understand as we look throughout this portion of
scripture in these few verses this morning, that we see the
character here, Mary, that she's magnifying the Lord. In
your life and in my life, how are we doing in magnifying the
Lord? What is it that we most talk about? We're preaching
through. I haven't been there in a while, but on Sunday
mornings, we've been going through the book of James here
in 2026. And by God's grace, we'll get back there here in
the next couple of weeks. But you think about that a number
of weeks ago or a number of months ago at this point, I
shared with you some of the statistics of how many words
are spoken by the, on average, by individuals in a day. And I
asked this question, how many of those words that we speak per
day are about magnifying the Lord, about rejoicing and about
praising our God? See, let God be magnified. And we find that
when we focus on his person, when we get into the presence
of God, when we know him the way that he desires for us to
know him, then what happens? We begin to talk about it. We
begin to magnify him. Of course, the list here is not
exhaustive with regard to all of the character traits of our
God and all of his attributes are not contained in these few
verses that we're looking at this morning. But you
understand that in just a few verses that Mary in her giving
this, this declaration of her magnifying the Lord and her
spirit rejoicing in God, my Savior, that she's focusing on
the person who God is. This morning, we need a renewed
glimpse of our God. We need to, as the psalmist said, to stand
in awe of our God. On the right-hand side of our bulletin
this morning is a little image there, how great thou art. The
choir, the ensemble sang, how great, how good. Listen, our
God is a great God and he's worthy of our praise and we
need to stand in awe of him. And you say, but pastor, I have
this and I have that. I understand life and God does as
well. We need to magnify the Lord. We need to exalt him and
lift him up to make him known. And I will magnify the Lord as
Mary did when I focus on his person. Number two, I will
magnify the Lord when I focus on his provision, on his
provision. Now, oftentimes when we think about provision, we
think about maybe those temporal things, the monetary things, we
think of provision in that sense. But I want you to notice
that as we look at this text of scripture, that really the
provision that we'd focus on is really not anything that's
monetary or something that's temporal. And you think about
the provision of God. Listen, he has given to us all things
that pertain unto life and godliness. He has provided
everything that we need. The greatest need of humanity was a
savior. The greatest need of humanity was a savior. And God
provided that. But I want you to understand, and I believe
that you would stand and testify with me this morning,
that God has met my greatest need in saving my soul, but he
also meets all of our needs. The Bible tells us in the book
of Matthew that we don't have to give thought for all of
these things. Why? Because God knows that we have need of
them and he's going to provide for us. Listen, the
psalmist said, the Lord is my shepherd, I shall not want. The
shepherd knows how to provide for his sheep. Amen. And the
shepherd is going to provide. He leads them into those green
pastures. He leads them beside the still waters. Why? Because
he knows what the need of the sheep is. And for us this
morning, we understand that when we focus on the person of
who our God is, but then we focus on his provision. Listen,
there are many times in which people complain about the
provision of God. I have this, but I
I wish I had that. How about the children of Israel? Manna. Brother Tim finished with
it in Sunday school this morning. Manna from heaven. I mean angel's food. Right? Miraculous
every day. Manna. God's provision. Oh I remember when we were back in Egypt and we had fish
and we had garlic and leeks and onions. It wouldn't be on my list. You know what I'm
saying? Those aren't the things I would think of to write about or to say about but that's
what they say. In our soul doth loathe. It means to hate, to despise. That was God's
provision. That was God's provision. His miraculous provision. And we find here that as we begin
to focus on what God has done. Listen, God has been so good to us. To give us all the
things that we need but we think about the spiritual provision that God has given to
us. I thank God every day of my life for saving my soul. But then I thank God for
giving me a Bible. I thank God for the Holy Spirit of God who indwells me. And the ministry
of the Holy Spirit. Listen, we understand the importance. He says walk in the Spirit
and you shall not fulfill the lust of the flesh. That the Spirit of God is the earnest
of our inheritance and His Spirit communes with our spirit and He teaches us and He guides
us in all truth. He's our comforter. I mean hallelujah for what He's done for us. His
provision. Notice first in the text of scripture as we think about magnifying the Lord and
I will as Mary magnify the Lord when I focus on His provision. The first of these is given
to us in verse 47 when we understand my salvation. She says and my spirit hath rejoiced in God
my Savior. I wonder this morning can you say that the Lord is my Savior. I know I mentioned
a moment ago about Psalm 23 the Lord is my shepherd. Listen Jesus is the Savior of the
world. But it's a personal situation. He died for the sins of the world. His provision for
salvation. Listen He's not willing that any should perish but that all should come to
repentance. We understand that He says that His will is that all men would be saved and
come to the knowledge of truth and we find that God has provided. But Mary says my spirit
hath rejoiced in God and those next that next word is so important my Savior. And this morning
it's absolutely imperative that each one of us that are present here today could stand
and testify and say God is my Savior. There was a day in my life I mentioned by way of
introduction that in just a couple of weeks it will be 29 years since God saved my soul.
And I'm so thankful for the fact that I could say that God is my Savior. I'm so thankful
that I can say as the songwriter this morning when we sang that song when we all get to
heaven or when the roll is caught up yonder excuse me and He says that He knows that He
will be there. You remember hearing that roll call in school when you were a child you're in
school they used to call roll and they call attendance right now I think you go to college
and they don't even care if you're there or not as long as you pay your bill you know. But the
reality is that there was attendance there was like a roll call and you would hear your name
and they always the first of the year every time we'd go into class Christopher and I'd say Chris
and my mom had no idea that I did that in school amen. And because I'd go home and she'd keep
calling me Christopher and that's perfectly fine but at school I was Chris and I would raise my
hand I'm here present accounted for right. When the roll is caught up yonder I'll be there. Mr.
Black had that confidence by the way it wasn't in his works you know there's a lot of places
that teach a works based salvation. Not only is it not biblical but you absolutely have no
assurance. How could you ever know if you really did enough. I'm so thankful that the Bible says
that not by works of righteousness which we have done but according to his mercy he hath begotten
us. For by grace are you saved through faith and that not of your not of yourselves sorry and not
of works lest any man should boast. And I'm so thankful this morning for the truth of God's Word
with regard to salvation and here Mary says that my spirit hath rejoiced in God my Savior. This
morning if you cannot say with certainty that the Lord is your Savior that he has saved you that you
have a time and place a known situation in your life as Jesus said to Nicodemus you must be born
again. Can I tell you that today is the day of salvation. You trust Christ today as your personal
Savior understanding that you're a sinner and that he is the Savior and he meets that need his
provision. I'm thankful for it. I think about his provision I see it in verse 48 notice what Mary
says for he hath regarded the lowest state of his handmaiden for behold from henceforth all
generations shall call me blessed. I want you to think about verse 48 and what Mary is saying here
we think about his provision listen God knows your frame. The Bible tells us that he knows that we're
but dust. He's the creator we're the creation. God made us and he says it says here for he hath
regarded the lowest state of his handmaiden. Listen God knows exactly where you are. He knows
exactly what you're going through. He knows every care of your heart and he says this casting all
your care upon him for he careth for you. Cast thy burdens upon the Lord and he shall sustain
thee. What wonderful promises we have from God and he knows. See when I think about the provision
sometimes we go through life and say well just no one understands no one knows. God does. God does.
You say but I have something that I just can't even share with anybody. It's so heavy. God knows
and not only does God know but God cares and God invites you to bring that to him and he promises
you that he'll sustain you. He knows your frame. He knows that we're but dust. He knows exactly what
every single one of his children are facing and dealing with. Isn't that wonderful? If you have
children this morning there are times no doubt as you're raising your children that you would look
and you'd be able to see that man there's something with that child. There's something in their life.
There's something they're struggling with. You could just tell from their countenance. You can
tell from their expressions, their tone of voice, whatever it may be and you know listen that's with
small amount of knowledge and wisdom. Our God who knows all things who is omniscient. He knows
everything and he knows our frame and we can rejoice in knowing as we think about his provision
that he loves us anyway. Can you imagine? He loves us and he cares about us. Number three he says or
she says this in verse 49, for he that is mighty hath done to me. Notice this it says great things.
Now we could spend hours talking about the great things that God has done for us. It starts with
salvation but then you think about all the great things and Mary just simply summarizes it and we
understand this morning with every single one of us that your list of great things that God has
done with you or for you is going to be different than someone else's list of the great things that
God has done for you but can I tell you, can I remind you this morning that he that is mighty
hath done to me great things. Praise God for his work in your life and in my life and what he's
done for us and I want you to consider this morning when we focus on the great things that
God's done for us we're going to magnify him. Why? Because we recognize that it's God's good hand
that's done those things. That's where we see as David said, taste and see that the Lord
is good. God is good and he's done to us great things. I hope this morning for just a moment
of time you can in your mind you can race back and you can consider some of the great things that
God has done for you. You can think about the the great ways in which God has answered prayer.
Something happened this morning I haven't even had opportunity to share it with Holly yet
and I'm not going to share it with you publicly but I want you to know that this morning
somebody called me on the phone and God answered prayer specifically. I thank God for that. Great
things that he's done that he hears you and he answers you and there's times in your life
that you pray and God answers. Listen, don't minimize that. It's amazing to consider that the
God of the universe cares about you and cares about me and that he listens to our prayers
and that he answers specifically. Praise God. I've learned to thank God for the no's.
Not this no's but the no. There's times in which God says no. Have you ever experienced it?
There's times in which God shuts a door. Have you ever experienced it? And here's what I tell
people all the time. Listen when God closes a door you know what he did right there? He provided you
with clear direction. Now don't be foolish and try to kick the door in. Amen? How many of you
done that before too? Amen? But you understand there's times that God says no.
God knows what you need. He knows what I need. Sometimes we think we know better. Sometimes
you pray and I pray and we say now God it'd be really good if you answered it just
like this. God doesn't need your help nor mine. Sometimes God says no and that's okay
because through that God is to be glorified. You know sometimes when God says no we can
get discouraged in that moment but then we go just a little while later and we see how
God said no there so that he could give us a greater yes here. Amen? Now if you've walked
with God for any period of time you've experienced something like that. So that the next time
God says no in your life it helps you to continue on trusting him expecting that he'll continue
to work and give you exactly what you need. He's done great things for us. It's absolutely
amazing. I mean just sit back and think. The songwriter said this, count your blessings
name them one by one. Amen? I know a lot of times that the month of November, the Thanksgiving
time in America that we maybe take some extra time to focus on the importance of thanking
God but every day of your life you ought to be thanking God. I start my prayer life every
day by adoring him and just rehearsing who he is, his attributes, his character and then
I begin to thank him. Listen God's been so good to you and to me. He's done great things
for us. Praise God for it. And then I want you to notice what Mary says in verse 53.
She says this, he hath filled the hungry with good things. And I just want to focus on the
first part of that verse. We find that here you could no doubt make various applications.
You could think about the physical provision and that's fine. But I want you to see here
where it says that he hath filled the hungry with good things. See in Matthew chapter number
five and verse number six as Jesus is preaching and the sermon on the mount and we find that
he makes this statement that's so important for us to understand. Blessed are they which
do hunger and thirst after righteousness. And then notice what it says for they shall
be filled. Who's going to be filled? Well they that hunger and thirst after righteousness.
As we think about this idea in verse 53 I would say that he meets our needs but not
just our physical needs but the greater than our physical needs he meets our spiritual
needs. Feasting on manna from heaven the song writer said. You think about the Bible. You
think about the fact that God has given to us this morning a Bible. I mean the whole
canon of scripture. And you this past week you read as much of the Bible as you really
wanted to. Amen? You learned as much about God from his word as you really wanted to.
And this morning when we think about this declaration of Mary and her magnifying the
Lord she says that he hath filled. Notice it says there in Luke 1 in verse number 53
he hath filled the hungry with good things. Now we understand what it is to be hungry.
Some of you are saying I'm hungry right now physically. Lunch is soon. But we have this
built in kind of time clock in our bodies of we get hungry every so often. Some of us
more frequently than others. Some would say my son my children they never stop being hungry.
And some would say little kids I'm starving. You ever hear somebody say that? And you're
like you're not starving. I promise you. You are not starving. I say sometimes this.
I say listen it's not the last meal. It's not the last supper. We're going to eat again
at some point. But I wonder how often are we hungry for God? How often are we hungry
for God's word? I wonder if there's ever been a time in our lives that we said I'm starving
spiritually. Like I just need to hear a word from God. I just need to, man I just need
God to meet that need spiritually for me. And when I'm, listen when you're hungry you
know what you do? Listen I know what I do when I'm hungry. I go over there to the refrigerator
and I open that thing up. Right? How many of you understand? And then you shut it. And
I go to the pantry and I open that up. Right? In our pantry you cannot open our pantry without
somebody else knowing. It squeaks. There's no secrecy. I'm telling you. That thing squeaks
open. What are you doing? Nothing. You understand what I'm saying? You know what you're doing.
You're hungry. And then I'll say to Holly I'm hungry. There's nothing to eat. Now there's
plenty to eat. Just not what you want at that moment. Right? Have you ever been there?
Because you don't want carrots. You don't want celery. Now some of you are like that's
what I want. Good for you. We were in West Virginia and I think it was Joseph he said
maybe it was Brianna I just want a plate of celery. And I'm like alright no it was Joseph
said that. Who are you? You have never eaten celery and like I've never seen you eat it.
And I said okay we'll take care of it. When we go to the restaurant we'll stop over there
and we'll get a bag of celery for you and then we're going to go in and eat a good supper.
No we didn't do that. That'd be rude. But listen we understand there's some things that
we do when we're hungry physically. Right? Are you hungry spiritually? So you know what?
I just need to go get my Bible. I need to spend some time with God. I need to get fed
from God. I'm not going to just check a box. I'm not just going to get my Bible reading
booklet out that I'm checking a box and just kind of go through the motions. No. I want
to hear from God. Because I'm hungry for God. The Bible tells us in Psalm 78 we won't take
the time to read all of it but we find that over there that the Scriptures teach us about
the fact that God tells them that He would fill them. He told them to open their mouth
and He would fill it and what a blessing to think about the provision of our God and to
think about the way that God will meet your need spiritually. This morning how are we
doing in magnifying the Lord? See I want to be in the place where Mary is where we could
say my soul doth magnify the Lord. I said Psalm 78 it's Psalm 81. Those of you that
are still looking for it. Psalm 81. I gave you the wrong reference. Psalm 81. And here's
what God said. I am the Lord thy God which brought thee up out of the land of Egypt.
Open thy mouth wide and I will fill it. But my people would not hearken to my voice and
Israel would none of me. I believe there's physical and also spiritual application there.
And what I want to convey to you this morning is just as Mary magnified the Lord the result
of her focusing on the person of God. Who He is. And on the provision of God. What He
has done. That for each of us this morning if we would turn our eyes upon Jesus as the
songwriter said. If we would just really get a fresh view of God and stand in awe of Him.
And as Mary focused on the person of God as we would do that then we too would magnify
the Lord. If we would take some time to rehearse the great things that God has done for us
not only His person but His provision. And yes we could speak about the temporal worldly
provision that He's provided for us. The food and the water and the raiment and the shelter
and all of those wonderful things. And I don't in any way mean to minimize those. Those are
amazing things that God has done for us. But then we also think about the spiritual
provision. Can I tell you when we focus on those things I believe that it will cause
us to magnify the Lord. And I believe that as the psalmist said in Psalm 70 and verse
number 4 let God be magnified. That for every one of us here this morning. Yes Mary she
said my soul does magnify the Lord. I hope that each one of us would say you know what
this week I want to magnify the Lord. Tomorrow when I go to the workplace when I have that
meeting when I have that appointment when I see those wherever it is I want to magnify
the Lord. I want to seize the opportunities that God would give me to speak about how
great He is and how wonderful He is and what He's done for me. Because great is the Lord
and greatly to be praised. With God's help and as we focus on these things I believe
this morning that like Mary we too can magnify the Lord. Let us pray. Father we love you.
We thank you for loving us. We thank you for the passage of scripture that we've had
the opportunity to work through this morning.
And God, we thank you for who you are.
We thank you for what you've done for us.
And I pray that as we go throughout the remainder
of this day and this week, Lord, in our lives,
that we'd be mindful of the opportunity
and responsibility that we have to magnify you,
to exalt you, to lift you up, to make you known.
And I pray, God, that you would help us,
encourage us, and strengthen us.
Lord, maybe this morning,
as we've examined the portion of scripture,
we've been honest with ourselves,
and your spirit has convicted us in some areas
in which we have maybe fallen short.
We've not magnified you like we should.
Lord, I pray that you'd help us
to get those things right with you.
Lord, help us to respond in obedience.
And Lord, that we'd be doers of the word
and not hearers only.
Father, if there's one that's here
that's not sure of heaven,
that greatest need of all of humanity
is to be saved by the grace of God.
I pray that in just a moment,
as we have our invitation,
they'd come and let us take a Bible
and show them how they could know for sure
that heaven is their home.
Lord, I pray that in these moments of invitation
that you would work as only you can,
help us to be doers, and we'll thank you for it.
In Christ's name we pray.
Would you stand with me?
Heads are bowed, eyes are closed.
In just a moment,
Kimberly's gonna play on the piano
a song of invitation,
giving you an opportunity to respond
to the preaching of God's word.
If you're a man here this morning
and you're not sure of heaven,
Brother Mark is here in the front.
He's got a Bible with him
and he'd love to be able to take a Bible
and show you how you could know for sure
that heaven is your home.
And if you're a lady,
Holly is here on the front.
She's got a Bible
and she'd be more than happy to take a Bible
and show you how you could know for sure
that heaven is your home.
Maybe you just need to come and talk to the Lord,
magnify the Lord.
As Kimberly plays,
the altar is open.